<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Draft on Ecological Foodways</title>
    <link>/draft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Draft on Ecological Foodways</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/draft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>agri-urban dynamics</title>
      <link>/draft/agri-urban-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draft/agri-urban-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>The connection of urban evolution to shifting foodways Topics:
 The Green Revolution: decline in labor demand and consolidation of farmlands lead to migration of farm workers to urban centers and character of cities at different scales The Civil War and Pacific Imperialism: the fight over slavery driven practices of the south lead to a transition of plantation agrictulture in the south pacific islands controlled by US interests American colonial land aquisition: disenfranchisement of First Peoples of the Americas were strongly dictated by perspectives on food and land-use, with Spanish, British, French and Dutch, and eventually United States, interests dominating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Review* Ke Kumu: The Source of Hawaiian Sustainability</title>
      <link>/draft/2018-06-17-ahupuaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draft/2018-06-17-ahupuaa/</guid>
      <description>The structure of ahupua’a as trusteeships The communities of the Hawaiian islands devloped organizational structures with sustainability as a focus. Through a animistic socio-religious worldview, the relationship among Hawaiians and between Hawaiians and the natural environment could be shaped and adapted by the concepts of ohana (family), kapu (sacredness) and mana (power).
Communities within defined districts (ahupua’a) were comprised of
 mokupuni: islands moku   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sassafrass a disenfranchised southern staple</title>
      <link>/draft/sassafras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draft/sassafras/</guid>
      <description>Ecology Understory tree often occurring at margins.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>poke sallet</title>
      <link>/draft/poke-sallet.rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draft/poke-sallet.rmd/</guid>
      <description>“… probably the best known and most widely used wild vegetable in America.”
 Euell Gibbons (needs verification)  Characteristics, Ecology, History  Phytolacca americana Phytolaccin Native to North America (also possibly found in Africa) Appalachian staple Associated with poor, rural south (e.g. “Poke Salad Annie”) Exported to Europe as an ornamental Used by the Algonquin for dye Civil War Era Letters possibly written in Pokeberry ink   Pigeon Berry  Eaten in large quantities by passenger pigeons   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugar cane and the southern influence on Pacific Imperialism</title>
      <link>/draft/2018-06-12-pineapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/draft/2018-06-12-pineapple/</guid>
      <description>Sugar Cane  Sugar was the driving force in colonization of the New World, the dominance of Great Britain in the West Indies In the South and the North, sugar was a highly lucrative industry that drove slave trade Sugar cane was the primary food that drove land conversion and industry in Hawaii A group of American entrepreneurs and missionaries who were largely built on sugar interests eventually orchestrated significant blows to the Hawaii monarchy This included the Reciprocity Treaty, which opened Hawaiian sugar markets to the US, and the Bayonett Treaty, including the abdication of Queen Lili’o’kalani Queen Lili’o’kalani contested her abdication and with support from the Clevland Administration, a former confederate, southern democratic senator, James H.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>