<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ecological Foodways</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ecological Foodways</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:25:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How the pineapple connects the South to the North in Hawaii</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-06-12-pineapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-06-12-pineapple/</guid>
      <description>Pineapple casserole
 Pineapple Casserole at a Southern Funeral  Pacific Imperialism  Characteristics, Ecology, History  Bromeliad Native to South America Scientific name is derived from a native word for tasty fruit Transported by natives to the Carribean Encountered by Cristopher Columbus Hospitality: Rareity and association with returning seamen   Sugar and Other Foods for Colonization  New England missionaries and entrepreneurs Hospitality foods to re-inforce invasion James Hunnewell Peter Cushman Jones Sanford Dole   Colonial Foods become Imperial Foods  Hawaiian League Teddy Roosevelt Henry Cabot Lodge   The Quest for Annexation  Bayonet Treaty New Lands Resolution Hawaiian Organic Act Annexation Statehood   Imperial Foods become Industrial Foods  James D Dole C&amp;amp;H The Big Five Hawaii Companies Matson Shipping   US “Apologies” and the Rights of the Disenfranchised  1988 Civil Liberties Act - Japanese Internment (Reagan) 1993 Hawaiian Apology Resolution (Clinton) 1997 Tuskegee Experiment (Clinton) 2008 Slavery Jim Crow Laws Apology Resolution (Obama) Apologies explicitely written to not have legal impact David Akaka (Senator Hawaii, Deceased Apr 6 2018)   James H Blount: An Unlikely Ally of  Blount Report “Freedom does not necessarily mean freedom from alien domination, bot unly a change of masters deemed by the new master beneficial to the ‘slave’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunting and First Peoples</title>
      <link>/blog/deer_hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/deer_hunting/</guid>
      <description>Pineapple Casserole at a Southern Funeral  Pacific Imperialism  Characteristics, Ecology, History  Bromeliad Native to South America Scientific name is derived from a native word for tasty fruit Transported by natives to the Carribean Encountered by Cristopher Columbus Hospitality: Rareity and association with returning seamen   Sugar and Other Foods for Colonization  New England missionaries and entrepreneurs Hospitality foods to re-inforce invasion James Hunnewell Peter Cushman Jones Sanford Dole   Colonial Foods become Imperial Foods  Hawaiian League Teddy Roosevelt Henry Cabot Lodge    Imperial Foods become Industrial Foods  James D Dole C&amp;amp;H The Big Five Hawaii Companies Matson Shipping   Modern Movement for First People’s Rights  Bearsears National Monument    Other Foods Common between the South and Hawaii  Pig roast Sweet potato Greens (Taro, Poke, Collards, Mustards)   Southern Sugar and Pineapple Production  American Sugar Refining Connection to African Slave Trade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Native Foodways</title>
      <link>/blog/mapping_foodways/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/mapping_foodways/</guid>
      <description>Pineapple Casserole at a Southern Funeral  Pacific Imperialism  Characteristics, Ecology, History  Bromeliad Native to South America Scientific name is derived from a native word for tasty fruit Transported by natives to the Carribean Encountered by Cristopher Columbus Hospitality: Rareity and association with returning seamen   Sugar and Other Foods for Colonization  New England missionaries and entrepreneurs Hospitality foods to re-inforce invasion James Hunnewell Peter Cushman Jones Sanford Dole   Colonial Foods become Imperial Foods  Hawaiian League Teddy Roosevelt Henry Cabot Lodge    Imperial Foods become Industrial Foods  James D Dole C&amp;amp;H The Big Five Hawaii Companies Matson Shipping   Modern Movement for First People’s Rights  Bearsears National Monument    Other Foods Common between the South and Hawaii  Pig roast Sweet potato Greens (Taro, Poke, Collards, Mustards)   Southern Sugar and Pineapple Production  American Sugar Refining Connection to African Slave Trade?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poke Sallet</title>
      <link>/blog/poke_sallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/poke_sallet/</guid>
      <description>“… probably the best known and most widely used wild vegetable in America.”
 Euell Gibbons (needs verification)  Characteristics, Ecology, History  Phytolacca americana Phytolaccin Native to North America (also possibly found in Africa) Appalachian staple Associated with poor, rural south (e.g. “Poke Salad Annie”) Exported to Europe as an ornamental Used by the Algonquin for dye Civil War Era Letters possibly written in Pokeberry ink   Pigeon Berry  Eaten in large quantities by passenger pigeons   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pineapple flavor of southern hospitality and human rights</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Pineapple Casserole at a Southern Funeral Pacific Imperialism Characteristics, Ecology, History  Bromeliad Native to South America Scientific name is derived from a native word for tasty fruit Transported by natives to the Carribean Encountered by Cristopher Columbus Hospitality: Rareity and association with returning seamen  Sugar and Other Foods for Colonization  New England missionaries and entrepreneurs Hospitality foods to re-inforce invasion James Hunnewell Peter Cushman Jones Sanford Dole  Colonial Foods become Imperial Foods  Hawaiian League Teddy Roosevelt Henry Cabot Lodge  The Quest for Annexation  Bayonet Treaty New Lands Resolution Hawaiian Organic Act Annexation Statehood  Imperial Foods become Industrial Foods  James D Dole C&amp;amp;H The Big Five Hawaii Companies Matson Shipping  US &amp;ldquo;Apologies&amp;rdquo; and the Rights of the Disenfranchised  1988 Civil Liberties Act - Japanese Internment (Reagan) 1993 Hawaiian Apology Resolution (Clinton) 1997 Tuskegee Experiment (Clinton) 2008 Slavery Jim Crow Laws Apology Resolution (Obama) Apologies explicitely written to not have legal impact David Akaka (Senator Hawaii, Deceased Apr 6 2018)  James H Blount: An Unlikely Ally of  Blount Report &amp;ldquo;Freedom does not necessarily mean freedom from alien domination, bot unly a change of masters deemed by the new master beneficial to the &amp;lsquo;slave&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/blog/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using go templates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1-install-hugo&#34;&gt;Step 1. Install Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;hugo releases&lt;/a&gt; and download the
appropriate version for your os and architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More complete instructions are available at &lt;a href=&#34;/overview/installing/&#34;&gt;installing hugo&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;move-static-content-to-static&#34;&gt;Move static content to &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with &lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; will be copied as-is to the &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; output. Hugo keeps all static content under &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;. You should therefore move it all there.
With Jekyll, something that looked like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/
    ▾ images/
        logo.png
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>